Beatrice Asense

https://www.linkedin.com/in/beatrice-asense/

SUMMARY

Driven, passionate, and goal-oriented individual capable of using creativity and organization to work independently and also collaborate with others in order to work effectively. Patient Math Teacher with resourceful and engaging teaching style demonstrated over 10 years of academic experience. Caring and hardworking professional with exceptional work ethic and commitment to cultivating productive learning environments to drive student progress and comprehension.

SKILLS

Excellent communication, Great customers service, People management, Well rounded in team building in collaborative environment, Positive Reinforcement Strategies, Learning Management Systems, Positive Role Model and Mentor, Driving.

EDUCATION

Humber College

Developmental Services Worker

- Psychology.
- o Introduction to developmental disabilities.
- Intervention techniques.
- Educational strategies.
- o Community orientation.
- o College read and writing skills.
- o Introduction to art and science.

Valley View University

Bachelor of Education in Mathematics

- Educational psychology.
- Algebra and Calculus.
- Technology in the classroom.
- o Introductory analysis.

St. Louis College of Education

Diploma in Basic Education

- Principles and practice of education.
- o Child and adolescent development and learning.
- o Principles and methods of teaching in basic schools.

EXPERIENCE

Osei Tutu Senior High School

Teacher

Kumasi Sept 2019 – Sept 2022

- Prepare lessons and activities for 200 students, Explain math concepts strategies, Develop and organize classroom materials, Assign homework, Assist students with any difficulties or concerns, Prepare students for quizzes and test, Grade assignments, test, and exams to asses students.
- o Scheduled appointments with parents to discuss student progress and classroom behavior.
- Utilizes Personal Outcome Measures to assist people in achievement of Outcomes.
- o Performs all duties and responsibilities in a professional manner.
- Developed and distributed study guides to reinforce lecture details and help 200 students with test preparation.

Toronto, Ontario, Canada Sept 2023 – Apr. 2024

Email: setorasense1@gmail.com

Mobile: (437)-244-2362

Techiman, Ghana Aug 2014 – Jul. 2017

Kumasi, Ghana Sept 2010 – Jul. 2013

• Bronkron Municipal Assembly Junior High School

Teacher

Tepa, Ghana Jan 2017 - Jan 2019

- Prepare lessons and activities for 40 students, Explain math concepts strategies, Develop and organize classroom materials, Assign homework, Assist students with any difficulties or concerns, Prepare students for quizzes and test, Grade assignments, test, and exams to asses students.
- o Supported students physical, mental, and social development using classroom games and activities.
- Kept 40 students on-task with proactive behavior modification and positive reinforcement strategies.
- o Provides respectful services and support to people with intellectual disabilities.
- Utilizes Personal Outcome Measures to assist people in achievement of Outcomes.

Tepa Senior High School

Tepa, Ghana

Jan 2016 - Jan 2017

Teacher

- Prepare lessons and activities for 200 student, Explain math concepts strategies, Develop and organize classroom materials, Assign homework, Assist students with any difficulties or concerns, Prepare students for quizzes and test, Grade assignments, test, and exams to asses students.
- Supported student physical, mental, and social development using classroom games and activities.
- Utilizes Personal Outcome Measures to assist people in achievement of Outcomes.
- Performs all duties and responsibilities in a professional manner.
- Kept students on-task with proactive behavior modification and positive reinforcement strategies.

HOBBIES

Cooking, Creating and sewing new designs.